{"test_questions": [[{"question": "\u03b2-amylase is", "opta": "endoenzyme", "optb": "exoenzyme", "optc": "saccharifying enzyme", "optd": "both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Juice clarification extraction is facilitated by using", "opta": "cellulases", "optb": "amylase", "optc": "inulinase", "optd": "lactase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysozyme is naturally present in", "opta": "egg white", "optb": "bacteria", "optc": "tears & milk", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enzymes act as antimicrobials", "opta": "by depriving an organism of a necessary metabolite", "optb": "by generating a substances toxic to the organism", "optc": "by attracting a cell wall component", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Trichoderma \u03b2-glucanase is reported", "opta": "to stabilize mashing", "optb": "to convert taste fractions of dextrins to fermentable sugars in beer", "optc": "to convert starch to dextrin", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bitter taste of the high protein materials is reduced by using", "opta": "invertase", "optb": "dectinase", "optc": "protease", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sulphydryl oxidase is used for", "opta": "discoloration", "optb": "clarification of images", "optc": "UHT milk off flavour removal", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\u03b1-amylase is an endo enzyme which requires", "opta": "Ca", "optb": "Cu", "optc": "Mn", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Liquefaction of starch to dextrin is carried out by", "opta": "\u03b1-amylase", "optb": "cellulase", "optc": "pectinase", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is true about rennet?", "opta": "It is a mixture of protease chymosin and pepsin", "optb": "It is a mixture of rennin and pepsin", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Milk digestibility is improved by using", "opta": "RNase", "optb": "lactase", "optc": "\u03b2-amylase", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following mainly serve to convert starch into high fructose corn syrup (HFCS)?", "opta": "\u03b1-amylase", "optb": "Gluco-isomerase", "optc": "Gluco-amylase", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysozyme", "opta": "catalyses hydrolysis of \u03b2-1-4 linkages between N-acetyl muranic acid and N-acetyl glucosamine in peptideoglycan", "optb": "catalyses hydrolysis of \u03b1-1-4 linkages between N-acetyl muranic acid and N-acetyl glucosamine in peptideoglycan", "optc": "catalyses hydrolysis of \u03b1-1-4 linkages between N-diacetyl muranic acid and N-diacetyl glucosamine in peptideoglycan", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hersperidinase is used for", "opta": "juice clarification", "optb": "juice debittering", "optc": "off flavour reduction", "optd": "RNA reduction in fish", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following metallic ion is there in ascorbic acid oxidase?", "opta": "Mg", "optb": "Fe", "optc": "Cu", "optd": "Mn", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the enzyme combination is commercially used for the removal of oxygen?", "opta": "Glucose oxidase-cellulase", "optb": "Glucose oxidase-catalase", "optc": "Glucose oxidase-lactase", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzyme used to reduce bitterness of grapes commonly contains", "opta": "\u03b1-L-rhamonosidase", "optb": "\u03b2-d-glucosidase", "optc": "\u03b2- galactosidase", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Citrus juice debittering can be carried out using", "opta": "limoninase", "optb": "inulinase", "optc": "anthocyanase", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following enzyme is responsible for causing vitamin B deficiency disease beriberi?", "opta": "Ascorbic acid oxidase", "optb": "Thiaminase", "optc": "Lipoxygenase", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Soya off flavour removal may be achieved using", "opta": "di acetyl reductase", "optb": "\u03b2- amylase", "optc": "aldehyde oxidase", "optd": "protease", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reduction in off flavour of beer is practiced through", "opta": "hersperidinase", "optb": "rnase", "optc": "invertase", "optd": "diacetyl reductase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Discoloration can be achieved by using", "opta": "sulphloydryl oxidase", "optb": "proteases", "optc": "anthocyanase", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The prosthetic group present in phenolase enzyme is", "opta": "Mg", "optb": "Cu", "optc": "Ca", "optd": "Fe", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enzymes degrade, alter or synthesize a food component through", "opta": "oxidation/reduction/isomerization", "optb": "hydrolysis/synthesis", "optc": "group transfer", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzyme \u03b2-galactosidase is also known as", "opta": "lactase", "optb": "EC3.2.1.23", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "isomerase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chymosin hydrolyses the bond between", "opta": "Alanine and glycine", "optb": "Phenyl alanine and methonine", "optc": "Glutamic acid and alanine", "optd": "Alanine and phenyl alanine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}